

Lorenzo D'Auria

AI & Robotics Engineer

🗣 Trieste, Italy · 🛗 31/12/1997 · 🛂 Italian

Iorenzodauria97@gmail.com

Skills

- Python
- C++
- ROS
- Azure
- Git
- Unix

Certifications

- MS Azure AZ-900
- MS Azure Al-900

Languages

Italian (Mother tongue)

English (B2)

Driving Licenses

A, B

Hobbies

Motorsport, Sailing

Profile

I am a Computer Science Engineer specialized in Robotics, Artificial Intelligence and Internet of Things. During this phase of my career, my main goal is to take part to professional and stimulating projects where I can learn and grow, but also make the difference.

Work Experience

AI & Robotics Engineer

Fincantieri, Trieste (TS)

Member of the Digital Innovation team for the study and development of new solutions in the fields of Robotics, Al and IoT, with the goal of improving the shipyard efficiency and security.

Skills involved: Python, C++, ROS, Azure, Git, Unix.

System Engineer (External Consultant)

Alten for Leonardo, Ronchi dei Legionari (GO)

Alten external consultant. Making part of the Leonardo Avionic Sensors Simulation team. Involved in the development of real-time systems for flight simulators.

Skills involved: C++, Git, Qt Framework, Unix.

Dec 2021 - Dec 2022

Gen 2023 - Today

FINCANTIERI



Education

MSc in Artificial Intelligence and Robotics

Sapienza University of Rome, Rome (RM)

Robotics, Autonomous and Mobile Robotics, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Vision and Perception, IoT. Course instructed in English.

Thesis: Navigation of Quadrotor UAVs among Obstacles with Formal Safety Guarantees.

Final grade: 110/110 cum laude.

Oct 2019 - Oct 2021

BSc in Electronic and Computer Engineering

University of Trieste, *Trieste (TS)*

Electronics, Logic Networks, Operating Systems, Computer Networks. Database.

Thesis: Stabilization of an Inverted Pendulum through a Reaction Wheel.

Final grade: 106/110.



Oct 2016 - Oct 2019